so the directory is a distributed
structure across the course it's not
centralized in one place like the bus so
not all requests have to go to the same
part of the directory each slice of the
directory will serve a set of blocks
where a slice of the directory is the
part of the directory that is next to a
particular core and that means that
different blocks will be served by
slices that are in different places and
that's how we achieve a higher bandwidth
because really each slice could operate
independently because it serves a
disjoint set of blocks what does a slice
do it has one entry for each block
served by that slice and the entry for a
block tracks which caches in the system
have this block in a non- invalid state
of course cu the Block in an invalid
state is like it's not in that cache at
all and the Order of accesses for a
particular block is determined by the
Home Slice for that block that's the
slice of the directory that has the
entry for this block we call that the
home slice of the directory so pretty
much accesses that go to the same block
are almost serialized in how they can
access their entry and the order in
which that happens is the order in which
the accesses are officially said to
happen note that with the directory
protocol the caches still have the same
States they did with Sno hoping it's
just now when we send a request to read
or write that request no longer goes on
a bus it gets sent via our Network to
the directory so we can have many
requests traveling to their individual
slices and then the directory figures
out what to do